A Guide to the Joseph C. McDaniel Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10553-t
Joseph C. McDaniel Papers 1953-1988
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10553-t
760 items
Mrs. Joseph C. McDaniel
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the Library by Mrs. J. C. McDaniel of Urbana, Illinois, on April 22, 1991.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of Dr. Joseph C. McDaniel(1912-1982), assistant professor of Horticulture at the University of Illinois, College of Agriculture, Urbana, Illinois, consists of 760 items (3 Hollinger boxes, one linear shelf foot), 1953-1988, and undated, chiefly the office file copies of McDaniel's professional correspondence and articles concerning horticulture (arranged by subject) by McDaniel. Also included in his papers is a botanical notebook (1969-1970) kept by McDaniel, research reports, publication file of articles published by him, magnolia registrations, and retired membership cards for the American Magnolia Society.
Some of the subjects discussed in the correspondence includes the following:
ash tree (1959 Jul 31; 1966 Oct 20, 25; 1971 Oct 18)
avocados (1958 Feb 18)
buckeyes (1969 Sep 24; 1971 Oct 7; 1973 Oct 11; n.d.)
cacti (1972 Dec 26; 1973 Jul 12; 1974 Nov 21)
chokeberries (1959 Feb 18)
crabapples (1959 May 25; 1960 Oct 12)
elms (1969 Feb 28)
golden rain trees (1971 Aug 6)
hackberries (1973 Oct 8)
hollies (1970 Mar 5, 11; 1971 Aug 11)
honeylocusts (1971 Nov 17; 1972 Jul 31)
horse apples (1973 Jul 20)
hydrangea (1960 Jul 14, 24, Sep 6, 15, Dec 13; 1961 Jan 9, 12, 27, Sep 19, Oct 25, Dec 4; 1965 Apr 21, May 17; 1967 Jun 26, Sep 11, Oct 25, 31, Nov 16; 1968 Apr 30, Jul 15; 1969 Jun 5, Aug 4; 1970 Jan 19; 1971 Oct 13, Nov 8; 1972 Jun 29; 1973 Nov 6; 1974 Jan 11, Jun 25; 1975 Jan 17; 1976 Apr 27; 1977 Aug 10; 1978 Feb 16; n.d.)
magnolias (1967 Sep 29; 1969 May 26; 1970 Jun 18; 1974 Mar 25, Apr 10 (both with articles attached); 1976 Apr 12; n.d.)
mulberries (1966 Sep 21; 1967 Jan 28)
nut grafting (1956 May 14)
pawpaws (1956 Apr 2, Jun 25; 1967 Apr 3)
pokeweeds (1974 Jan 10)
quinces (1958 Jan 13; 1972 May 10)
redbud trees (1970 May 18; 1971 Oct 28, Nov 2)
serviceberries (1974 May 13)
woody plants (1958 Nov 28)
yuccas (1969 Mar 31, Dec 11; 1970 Aug 10; 1971 Jan 5, Aug 20; 1973 Jan 8, Aug 7, Sep 13, 19, Oct 16, 19; 1974 Jan 23, Feb 4, 12, Nov 18; 1982 Aug 25)
Container List
- Articles: Bamboo, 1973, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Book Reviews, 1974, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Bottlebrush Buckeye, 1971-1972 (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Cacti, 1969, 1974, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Chip Budding and Grafting, 1959-1975, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Fruit Trees, 1948, 1953 (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Hollies, 1970-1980 (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Hydrangeas, 1960-1986, n.d. (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Landscape Plants, 1971-1976 (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Magnolias, 1963-1979; (4 folders) (Box Box 1)
- Articles: Magnolias, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Miscellaneous (General), 1966, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Miscellaneous (Partial), 1970-1981, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Miscellaneous Trees, 1970-1978, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Mulberries, 1981, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Pawpaws, 1971-1983, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Pecans and Other Nut Trees, 1953-1976, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Persimmons, 1960-1988, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Quinces, 1961, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Serviceberries, 1971-1975, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Shrubs, 1969-1974, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Witch-hazels, 1971, 1975, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Articles: Yuccas, 1969-1975, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Botanical Notebook kept by J. C. McDaniel, 1969-1970 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1956, 1958-82, n.d.; (6 folders) (Box Box 3)
- Magnolia Registration, 1972-1974 (Box Box 3)
- Publication File, 1966, 1973, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- U.S. Department of Agriculture Research Reports, 1968-1980 (Box Box 3)
- Retired Membership Cards for the American Magnolia Society, n.d. (Box Card File Tray 67)